Brenda Beck collection from Tamil Nadu, India
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 6: Ritual and practices, 1965-1969; 1976-1977
  - Subseries 7: Weddings
    - Maataari wedding rituals, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/40-42)
    - Maataari wedding rituals (Telegu speakers) (x4), Manuscript (Box-folder 21/43)
    - Naiyakan wedding rituals, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/44)
    - Pandiya Navitan rituals, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/45)
    - Mankalavarthu, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/46)
    - Tamarind branch, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/47)
    - Utaiyar rituals, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/48)
    - Vatuka Vannan rituals, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/49)
    - Veetar rituals, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/50)
    - Wedding of two trees, Manuscript (Box-folder 21/51)
- Series 7: Fieldwork and related works, 1964-1968
  - Diaries, Books 1-4, 1964-1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/1-2)
    Daily entries of Beck's activities throughout her stay in India. Including conversations with interviewees and the stories she collected.
  - Field notes basic sequence, January-April, 1965, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/3)
  - Field notes basic sequence, April-July, 1965, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/4)
  - Field notes basic sequence, July-September, 1965, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/5)
  - Field notes basic sequence, August-December, 1965-January, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/6)
  - Field notes basic sequence, November, 1965-February, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Field notes basic sequence, February-April, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/8)
  - Field notes basic sequence, May-September, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/9)
  - Field notes basic sequence, February, 1966 and June, 1966, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/10)
  - Index to field notes, Manuscript (Box-folder 22/11)
    The index of the core field notes of the social and religious structure of a Tamil-speaking community in South India which was used in writing D.Phil. Thesis, 1968.
    See Box 24
  - Sundaram answers to Brenda's letters, Manuscript (Box-folder 23/1-7)
    Sundaram's answers to various topics asked by Professor Brenda Beck.
  - Mackensie manuscripts, Madras, Manuscript (Box-folder 23/8-9)
  - Manuscript materials for sound recordings, Manuscript (Box-folder 23/10)
    Field notes describing recordings.
  - Index to field notes, Manuscript (Box 24)
    Card index to basic field note sequences.
    See Box 22 for notes.
    Field notes were used in Brenda Beck's Phil Thesis, Oxford 1964. See Box 26 for thesis.
  - Indices to graphic materials (Box 25)
    Small books containing the indices and description of graphic materials in the collection:
    Black-and-white negatives, 1964-1966
    Sundaram's black-and-white photos (contact sheets)
    Key to India slide files
    Original color photo notes
    Miscellaneous photos
  - Theses, 1964, 1968 (Box 26)
    Contains two theses submitted by Brenda Beck to the University of Oxford, England: The Examination of Marriage Ritual among selected groups in South India, 1964 and Social and Conceptual order in Koṅku: a Region in South India, 1968.
- Series 8: Graphic materials, 1964-2017
  - Subseries 1: Black-and-white negatives 1964-2017
    - afc2017050_cf11, 1964-66 All Photos and all Audio Tapes\Black and White photos\1965 B&W Photos\Scanned negatives India1965 B&W; 1295 jpegs and 2 file folders
      The following images are a subset of contact sheet available. The entire set of black-and-white prints can be viewed in the index. These are the portion of what AFC has in its holdings Box 25.
    - Wedding ceremony and YMCA, AFC 2017/050: PH01-01; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 32 images (Box 27)
      Images include a wedding ceremony in the village and the community center, The YMCA. See pages 7, 9, 11, 13, 15 and 17 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - YMCA and an Aiyupan Festival, AFC 2017/050: PH01-02; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 26 images
      Images of the YMCA along with an Aiyupan Festival with an elephant procession. Also included are images of different families in the village. See pages 17, 19, 21, 22, 23 25, 27, 29, and 31 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - Brenda Beck, social and political activites, AFC 2017/050: PH01-03; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 39 images
      Images include a Coming of Age ceremony, an anti Hindu demonstration, Republican day and villagers voting. Also included are Beck and families in the village. See pages 37, 39, 41, 43, 49, 51, and 53 in Black-and-white negatives index for images. See Box 21 for Coming of Age ceremony.
    - Families, temples and activities in Olapalayam, AFC 2017/050: PH01-04; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 30 images
      See pages 55, 57, 59, 61, 63 and 65 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - Sundaram Pandaram, temples and superstitious objects, AFC 2017/050: PH01-05; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 19 images
      See pages 69, 71, 73, 77, 79 and 81 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - Temples and village activities, AFC 2017/050: PH01-06; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 33 images
      Images include temples and temple offerings, pottery, ceremonies, gypsies and villagers. See pages 89, 91, 93, 97, 99, 101 and 103 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - Festivals, temples, and pujas, AFC 2017/050: PH01-07; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 37 images
      Images include villagers performing temple rituals including puja along with partaking in different festivals. See pages 105, 107, 109, 111, 113, 115, 119, 121, and 123 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - Mariamman Festival, AFC 2017/050: PH01-08; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 31 images
      Images include a procession to the temple along with a puja. Also includes images of the Mariamman Festival. See pages 127, 129, 131, 133, 135, 137, 139, and 141 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - Aiyar and Mudeliyars, puja and the Sivan temple, AFC 2017/050: PH01-09; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 35 images
      Images of the the different caste members visiting the temple and performing puja. See pages 143, 145, 147, 149, 151, 153, 155, 157, and 159 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - Rituals at the Sivan and Mariamman Temples, AFC 2017/050: PH01-10; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 36 images
      See pages 161, 163, 165, 167, 169, 171, 173, 175, 177, and 179 in Black-and-white negatives index for images. Also includes Brenda Beck and informant Pappamma.
    - The Kannpanasami Temples, and village activities, AFC 2017/050: PH01-11; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 32 images
      Images include The Kannpanasami Temple, pottery, possession, Nadar lineage festival and a Pariyan drummer. See pages 179, 181, 185, 187, 189, 191, 193, 195, and 197 in Black-and-white negatives index for images.
    - Wedding ceremony and caste members, AFC 2017/050: PH01-12; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 34 images
      Images include Sundaram, Beck, a wedding ceremony and villagers from the different caste systems. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-13; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 24 images
      See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-14; 35 mm black-and-white negatives, 25 images
      Images of the different villagers performing different activities including singing, riding a donkey and performing farming duties. Also includes the Olapalayam students and teachers on Independence Day. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-15; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 20 images
      Images of caste members including the Periasamy Grounder, Udaiyar Vannati, and Chekkili. Also includes of Rettivalasu, Gannapunam and village residents weaving thread. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Villager residents and the town, AFC 2017/050: PH01-16; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 28 images
      Images of a cloth shop, a puja, a library and temples. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-17; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 26 images
      Images include a Gounder family, an Aasari wedding, a wooden horse outside the Vangalamman temple, and kadai vidi. Also includes Sundaram's house, Brenda, Parani and family, and a group of children. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents and activities, AFC 2017/050: PH01-18; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 23 images
      Angalamman, a Nadar Temple and gods. Also includes Marimuttu preparing for the Angalamman story, an audience watching the performance, the current karnam and his family, and Sundaram's house. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents and activities, AFC 2017/050: PH01-19; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 40 images
      A puja, an Asani family, a group of children, a wedding and beach with Brenda and others, including fishermen. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents and activities, AFC 2017/050: PH01-20; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 39 images (Box 28)
      Images include Isuman kovil, the Sivan festival, Mudeliyars, Aiyars, funeral ceremonies and a religious ritual. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Towns, village residents and activities, AFC 2017/050: PH01-21; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 43 images
      Images include the Aiyaraian Temple, Tengalapetti, Madurai, Dumont and relatives, a waterway, horses, and pottery. Also includes Dr. Veluppilla, stone inscriptions, carvings, house 34, temples, and a Gounder drawing water. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Landscapes and activities, AFC 2017/050: PH01-22; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 30 images
      Images include stone inscriptions and carvings, house 34, temples, and a Gounder drawing water. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village resident, AFC 2017/050: PH01-23; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 31 images
      Images include a Udaiyar caste member, a shoe maker, a wedding, temples, stone carvings, harvest, farming and livestock. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-24; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 41 images
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-25; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 27 images
      Image includes village residents, stone inscriptions and carvings. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-26; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 18 images
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-27; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 38 images
      Images include village residents, houses, and gods. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-28; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 26 images
      Images of village residents performing rituals and working in a factory. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-29; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 32 images
      Images include village residents, rituals, wedding, funeral, and school children. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-30; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 33 images
      Images of village residents. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-31; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 32 images
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-32; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 44 images
      Images of village residents and statues. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents and activites, AFC 2017/050: PH01-33; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 9 images
      Some images include villagers performing rituals. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents and acitivities, AFC 2017/050: PH01-34; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 71 images
      Images used in Beck's publication, Three Twins. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH01-35; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 88 images
      Images used in Beck's book, Three Twins. See Black-and-white negatives index.
    - Sundaram's images
      - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH02-02; 35 mm black-and-white-negatives; 31 images (Box 29)
        Village residents and their houses. See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
      - Village and village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH02-03; 35 mm black-and-white-negatives; 34 images
        Buildings, temples and residents. See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
      - Village residents, AFC 2017/050: PH02-04; 35 mm black-and-white-negatives; 28 images.
        See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
      - Ceremony, AFC 2017/050: PH02-05; 35 mm black-and-white-negatives; 32 images
        Temples and statues along with residents participating in a ceremony. See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
      - Village residence, AFC 2017/050: PH02-06; 35 mm black-and-white-negatives; 35 images
        Villagers participating in a ceremony. See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
      - Villagers, AFC 2017/050: PH02-07; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 38 images
        Fisherman, statues and villagers participating in a ceremony. See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
      - Temples and statues, AFC 2017/050: PH02-08; 35 mm black-and-white negatives; 36 images
        Images of temples and statues and villagers. See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
      - Temples and statues, AFC 2017/050: PH02-09; 35mm black-and-white negatives; 16 images
        Images of temples, statues, and villagers. See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
      - The village, AFC 2017/050: PH02-10; 35 mm black-and-white-negatives; 35 images
        Images of the village and villagers. See Sundaram's black-and-white photos index.
  - Subseries 2: Color negatives
    - The Villagers, AFC 2017/050: PH03-01; 37 images color negatives (Box 30)
      Images that were used in Beck's book, Three Twins. See Box 25 for related images.
    - The Villagers, AFC 2017/050: PH03-02; 53 images color negatives
      Folk paintings and villagers. See See Box 25 for related images.
  - Subseries 3: Color slides
    - Slide ranges: PH04-01 - PH08-246 (Boxes 31-35)
    - A-C, AFC 2017/050: PH04-01 - PH06-153; 220 35mm color slides; A-PH04-01 - PH04-66; B-PH05 missing; C-PH06-001 - PH06-153 (Box 31)
      Images of agriculture scenes and ceremonies. See Key to India slides file index.
    - C, AFC 2017/050: PH06-154 - PH06-373; 220 35mm color slides; C-PH06-154 - PH06-373 (Box 32)
      Ceremonies (familial). See Key to India slides file index.
    - C-D, AFC 2017/050: PH06-374 - PH07-103; 220 35mm color slides; C-PH06-374 - PH06-486A; D-PH07-001 - PH07-103. (Box 33)
      Ceremonies (familial) and devi (female goddesses). See Key to India slides file index.
    - D-F, AFC 2017/050: PH07-104 - PH08-024; 220 35mm color slides; D-PH07-104 - PH07-301; F-PH08-001 - PH08-024 (Box 34)
      Devi (female goddesses) and folklore, folk art and dance. See Key to India slides file index.
    - F, AFC 2017/050: PH08-025 - PH08-246; 220 35mm color slides; F-PH08-25 - PH08-246 (Box 35)
      Devi, folklore, folk art, and dance. See Key to India slides file index.
    - Slide ranges: PH08-247 - PH15-126 (Boxes 36-40)
    - F, AFC 2017/050: PH08-247 - PH08-462; 217 35mm color slides; F-PH08-247 - PH08-462 (Box 36)
      Folklore, folk art, and dance. See Key to India slides file index.
    - G-H, AFC 2017/050: PH09-001 - PH10-095; 220 35mm color slides; G-PH09-001 - PH09-123; H-PH10-001 - PH10-095 (Box 37)
      Gods (male) and historical sites. See Key to India slides file index.
    - H, AFC 2017/050: PH10-96 - PH10-303C; 220 35mm color slides; H-PH10-096 - PH10-303C (Box 38)
      Historical sites. See Key to India slides file index.
    - H-I, AFC 2017/050: PH10-303D - PH11-070; 220 35mm color slides; H-PH10-303D - PH10-450; I-PH11-001 - PH-11070 (Box 39)
      Historical sites, murals and paintings. See Key to India slides file index.
    - I-O, AFC 2017/050: PH11-071 - PH15-126; 217 35mm color slides; I-PH11-071 - PH11-077; J-PH12-001 - PH12-029; K-PH13-001 - PH13-030; M-PH14-001 - PH14-024; O-PH15-001 - PH15-126 (Box 40)
      Murals and paintings, Olapalayam, Krishna's pastimes (for course lectures), maps and Olapalayam (more). See Key to India slides file index.
    - Slide ranges: PH15-127 - PH22-06 (Boxes 41-45)
    - O-P, AFC 2017/050: PH15-127 - PH16-171; 217 35mm color slides; O-PH15-127 - PH15-171; PH16-001 - PH16-171 (Box 41)
      Olapalayam and people. See Key to India slides file index.
    - P-R, AFC 2017/050: PH16-172 - PH17-076; 220 35mm color slides; P-PH16-172 - PH16-315; R-PH17-001 - PH17-076 (Box 42)
      People and rituals. See Key to India slides file index.
    - R-T, AFC 2017/050: PH17-077 - PH18-079; 220 35mm color slides; R-PH17-077 - PH17-322; T-PH18-01 - PH18-079 (Box 43)
      Rituals and temples. See Key to India slides file index.
    - T-X, AFC 2017/050: PH18-80 - PH21-26; 220 35mm color slides; T-PH18-80; U-PH19-001 - PH19-141; V-PH20-01 - PH20-33; X-PH21-01 - PH21-26 (Box 44)
      Temples, urban, and various friends. See Key to India slides file index.
    - X-Y, AFC 20174/050: PH21-27 - PH22-06; 19 35mm color slides; X-PH21-27; Y-PH22-01 - PH22-06 (Box 45)
      CBC crew and advertising. See Key to India slides file index.
- Series 9: Digital surrogates of sound recordings, 2005, The digital items described below were digitized by the donor. The collection does not include corresponding physical transcripts or analog recordings.
  - Potter's Story, 1 wav file (440.53 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. Potter's story was recorded in June 15, 1966 and can be found on recording AFC 2017/050: SR30. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Process God's from Temple, 1 wav file (36.57 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Process Gods To Temple, 1 wav file (19.22 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Process Gods To Temple Q, 1 wav file (20.78 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Calling spirits for possession, 1 wav file (10.28 MB): digital; 1 wav file (9.06 MB): digital; 1 wav file (18.44 MB): digital; Digital copies of this file were extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Brahman chants, 1 wav file (204.22 MB): digital; 1 wav file (204.74 MB): digital; Digital copies of this file were extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. The Brahman chants were recorded on April 4, 1965 and can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR34. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Brenda's fortune, 1 wav file (76.34 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording of Brenda's Beck fortune by a fortune teller, April 21, 1965, can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR32. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Fortune teller, 1 wav file (56.38 MB): digital; 1 wav file (109.5 MB): digital; Digital copies of this file were extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Cengotayan's story, 1 wav file (29.55 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. The story was recorded on April 21, 1965 and can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR32. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf06)
  - Songs and Anagalamman, 1 wav file (163.07 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Aiyar Gurukal, 1 wav file (56.5 MB): digital; 1 wav file (3.07 MB): digital; Digital copies of this file were extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR34 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Mangalavattu, 1 wav file (137.23 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR34 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Lullaby and kavadi songs, 1 wav file (181 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR34 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Crowd at singing at funeral, 1 wav file (18.95 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR20 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Crying songs, 1 wav file (81.23 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. Recordings can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR20, SR27 and, SR29. (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Papa's H Funeral, 1 wav file (53.98 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR20 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Paraiya songs at funeral, 1 wav file (169 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR20 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Nadaswaram/Nageshwaram and drums, 1 wav file (90.0 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR29 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Nasuvan Story by Sundaram, 1 wav file (28.2 MB): digital; A digital copy of this file was extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR29 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Raja story by Pappamal, 1 wav file (41.99 MB MB): digital; 1 wav file (41.9 MB): digital; Digital copies of this file were extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR29 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)
  - Mariyamman festival drumming, 1 wav file (8.84 MB): digital; 1 wav file (259 MB): digital; 1 wav file (64.7 MB): digital; Digital copies of this file were extracted from the original carrier by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes. The file path is provided. A recording can be found on AFC 2017/050: SR29 (Digital-carrier afc2017050_cf11)